A Guide to the Papers of Kenneth Brown, ca. 1870-1942
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Kenneth Brown ca. 1870-1942
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9732-a
4 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the Library in July 1971 from Jerry Showalter.
Biographical/Historical Information
The son of Franklin B. and Caroline Morrill Brown, Kenneth Brown (1868- ) was born in Chicago and lived in Europe as a youth. A University of Virginia alumnus and Harvard graduate, he worked on several newspapers including the Boston Journal and the New York Commercial Advertiser. In 1904 he married Demetra Vaka (1877-1946), a Byzantine Greek who had come to the United States at the age of 17. Together they went to Greece during World War I, interviewed King Constantine, Eleutherios Venizelos, and other leaders, and wrote about their observations. In 1921 the couple did a series of articles on Turkey. Mrs. Brown is known also for several novels and works of non-fiction, including Haremlik (1909), In the Shadow of Islam (1911), and In the Grasp of the Sultan (1916).
Scope and Content
This collection consists chiefly of scrapbooks of Kenneth, Francesca, and their mother Caroline Morrill Brown.
Contents List
- Scrapbook of Caroline Brown, containing clippings, re: Women's Clubs, woman suffrage, poems, etc. ca. 1870-ca. 1905 (Box 1)
- Clippings from scrapbook of Caroline Brown ca. 1870-ca. 1905 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Caroline Brown, containing chiefly concert programs ca. 1880-ca. 1890 (Box 1)
- Concert programs from scrapbook of Caroline Brown ca. 1880-ca. 1890 (Box 1)
- Scrapbook of Caroline Brown, chiefly of concert programs and newspaper clippings ca. 1871-ca. 1916 (Box 2)
- Concert programs and clippings from scrapbook of Caroline Brown ca. 1871-ca. 1916 (Box 2)
- Scrapbook of Kenneth Brown, containing clippings from The Magpie and newspapers that Kenneth Brown worked on, including a letter each from John Bannister Tabb and George Kennan 1893-1898 (Box 3)
- Clippings from scrapbook of Kenneth Brown 1893-1898 (Box 3)
- Scrapbook of Francesca Boone containing poems and quotations 1914 (Box 3)
- Clippings from scrapbook of Francesca Boone 1914 (Box 3)
- Scrapbook of Kenneth Brown, containing chiefly clippings from The Commercial Advertiser 1898-1899 (Box 4)
- Letters and invitations to Caroline Brown, Francesca Boone, and [Kenneth Brown] 1876-1942, 9 items (Box 4)
- Issues of "The Weary Pelican" by Kenneth Brown 1881-1883, 12 items (Box 4)
- Issues of "Illinois Abroad" by Kenneth Brown and B.P. Bourland 1882-1883, 12 items (Box 4)
- Issues of "L'Etourdi" by Kenneth Brown 1883, 2 items (Box 4)
- Issues of "Le Mois Illustré," "L'Hirondelle," and "Mes Impressions" by Kenneth Brown; "What a Parisian Thinks of Some American Children," in French and in English 1883, 6 items (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous items, including a lease of Caroline Brown and a certificate of citizenship of Caroline Brown 1881-1884, 11 items (Box 4)